Let’s now answer the two analysis questions
presented in this workbook project. First,
we want to know how many print statements will run
with the current code. Going through the list of
operands that will display in the for loop, the
loop runs six times with a different message for
the floor division operand on line 3 as part
of the if statement. Then, the print statement
on line 4 prints, and the code continues. That
print statement is the fifth print statement,
as the print statement on line 6 prints the
first four and the last operand. The second
question asks for the number of print statements
we will get if we change the continue on line 5 to
break. I will make that change. Since the code
will now break when the if condition is true,
we will not see the modulus operator print.
Thus, we should now see five print statements.
I will rerun the code, and we see five
print statements. One way to analyze code
with loops is to run through each iteration to
predict what will happen when the code runs.